7852 Sundown Dr. N.

727.686.7094

St. Petersburg, FL 33709

cristynewman7@gmail.com

Summary

I have over 20 years in the banking industry performing various jobs. In my current position, which I've enjoyed for over 15 years, I am a Corporate Trainer. I use my extensive knowledge to create manuals and guides, eLearning courses and conduct virtual and in-person training as needed on numerous topics including sales, service, systems, products and technical processes. I regularly test new programs, system updates and product releases, which is something I really have a passion for as it helps me to gain a deeper understanding of the material so that I can craft the best possible training courses and materials for the specific audience it is intended for. I enjoy learning and expanding my skills while helping make a difference within my organization.

Qualifications

- Lead project manager on 10-12 projects annually which include system and product releases, create and maintain over 135 procedures, 20+ eLearning courses, and 7 manuals.
- Create and maintain a suite of Storyline eLearning courses covering a range of topics including sales, service, products, regulations and compliance.
- Efficiently analyze products, processes and systems to create engaging training courses and materials that will enhance the learners comprehension.
- Conduct effective follow up, assessments and additional training to employees as needed.
- Effectively communicate with various teams to identify training needs, coordinate projects and ensure adherence to all policies and regulations.
- Proficient in Microsoft and the Google Suite of products as well as Adobe Sign and Articulate Storyline.

Education

♦ 1997-2001 Bachelors Degree in Business Management

Eckerd College St Petersburg, FL

Professional Experience

2005-Present

Corporate Trainer, floridacentral Credit Union

- Develop training curriculum on various topics including sales, service and product knowledge.
- Analyze new and current processes and systems, present solutions to management and implement changes while maintaining a strong focus on the end user interface and experience.
- Manage various projects to ensure necessary steps are completed in a timely manner.
- Create, update and maintain all technical guides, training courses and materials.
- Frequently conduct instructor led training and virtual training to groups of various sizes and backgrounds.
- Manage and update the (LMS) Learning Management System.
- Utilize Articulate Storyline to create engaging eLearning courses.

CRISTY NEWMAN

7852 Sundown Dr. N.

727.686.7094

St. Petersburg, FL 33709

cristynewman7@gmail.com

Professional Experience (continued)

2003-2005

Sales Manager, Amsouth Bank

- Manage and train branch employees.
- Interview and hire qualified applicants.
- Perform quarterly assessments and annual reviews.
- Conduct regular coaching sessions to develop employees in all areas of job performance.
- Offer new account, loan and investment solutions to customers.

2001-2003

Licensed Financial Specialist, Wachovia Bank

- Responsible for building client relationships by providing excellent customer service.
- Offer new account, loan and investment solutions to clients.
- Assist in the daily management of the staff.
- Mentor new hires to achieve sales goals.